Hello, everyone, and welcome back to another lesson here at EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎回到EnglishPod的另一节课。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And my name is Kathryn.
我是Kathryn。
So Marco, what are we talking about today?
那么Marco，我们今天要聊什么？
Today, we're talking about a very interesting topic.
今天我们要聊一个非常有趣的话题。
You've probably seen it on every TV show or American movie and it's a bachelor party.
你可能在每部电视剧或美国电影里都见过，那就是单身派对。
Uh-oh.
哦哦。
Yeah.
是啊。
I've heard bad things.
我听说过一些不好的事。
Bad things about a bachelor party.
关于单身派对的坏事。
Now, they can be fun, but at times, they can be a little bit too excessive, too much.
它们可以很有趣，但有时也会有点过头、太过分了。
But before we get started on the dialogue, why don't we take a look at vocabulary preview?
但在开始对话之前，我们先来看看词汇预览吧？
Vocabulary preview.
词汇预览。
Well, the first one we've got here is the topic of today.
嗯，我们第一个要讲的就是今天的话题。
This is the bachelor party.
这就是单身派对。
So what is a bachelor exactly?
那么“bachelor”到底是什么意思？
Right.
没错。
Well, a bachelor is a person who is not married, a single person, a single guy specifically,
嗯，“bachelor”指的是未婚的人，一个单身的人，特指单身男性，
right?
对吧？
All right.
好的。
So it's a man.
所以是指男人。
Man.
男人。
Before he's married.
在他结婚之前。
And a bachelorette.
还有“bachelorette”。
Okay.
好的。
Bachelor is a guy and a bachelorette is a girl.
“Bachelor”是男人，“bachelorette”是女人。
And so we don't really say bachelorette except when we're talking about this party.
我们平时不太说“bachelorette”，除非在谈论这种派对时。
Right.
对。
So a bachelor party is a party that a guy has the day before he's married or maybe two
所以“bachelor party”是男人在结婚前一天，或者结婚前两三天举办的派对。
or three days before he actually gets married.
So it's a night where all his friends get together, they go out, they have some drinks,
这是一个夜晚，他所有的朋友聚在一起，出去喝点酒，
they have some fun and just like the last extreme fun they will have, he will have before
找点乐子，就像他结婚前最后一次极致的狂欢。
he gets married.
All right.
好的。
And so it's all his guy friends.
而且都是他的男性朋友。
All his guy friends.
全是他的男性朋友。
Only guys, no girls.
只有男人，没有女人。
And the bachelorette party is only girls and it's when a girl's friends take her out before
而“bachelorette party”则只有女人，是女性朋友在她结婚前带她出去，
she gets married to celebrate her last night or two of being unmarried.
庆祝她未婚的最后一两晚。
Right.
对。
Exactly.
没错。
So not only guys' parties can get a little bit crazy but girls' bachelorette parties can
所以不只是男人的派对会有点疯狂，女人的单身派对
also get kind of crazy, right?
也会有点疯狂，对吧？
That's true.
确实如此。
So before we start talking about what exactly goes on at some of these parties, let's take
在我们开始讨论这些派对上到底会发生什么之前，让我们先
a listen to today's dialogue and hear what happens to our main characters.
听听今天的对话，看看我们的主角们发生了什么。
Hi honey.
嗨，亲爱的。
You'll never guess what.
你绝对猜不到。
My friends Julie and Alex are getting married.
我的朋友Julie和Alex要结婚了。
Wow.
哇。
That's great news.
真是好消息。
They're a great couple.
他们是很棒的一对。
I know.
我知道。
Anyways, I just talked to Alex's best man and he is organizing the bachelor party.
总之，我刚和Alex的伴郎聊过，他正在组织单身派对。
It's going to be so much fun.
一定会很好玩。
All the groomsmen are thinking up all the wacky and crazy things we're going to do that
所有伴郎都在想那天晚上我们要做的各种古怪疯狂的事。
night.
You aren't going to a strip club, are you?
你不会要去脱衣舞俱乐部吧？
I don't want you getting a lap dance from some stripper with the excuse that it's your
我可不想你以朋友派对为借口，让某个脱衣舞女给你跳膝上舞。
friend's party.
Oh, come on.
哦，别这样。
It's just some innocent fun.
这只是些无伤大雅的乐趣。
You know how these things are.
你知道这些事是什么样的。
We're going to play drinking games, get him some gag gifts and just have a good time.
我们会玩喝酒游戏，给他送些恶搞礼物，好好开心一下。
Nothing too over the top.
不会太过分的。
Well, I don't know.
嗯，我不知道。
Come on.
别这样。
If one of your friends was getting married, I wouldn't mind you going to a bachelorette
如果你的一个朋友要结婚，我不会介意你去参加单身女郎派对。
party.
Good, because my friend Wendy's getting married and I'm organizing her party.
很好，因为我的朋友Wendy要结婚了，我正在组织她的派对。
What?
什么？
All right, great.
好吧，太好了。
So apparently both of them have parties to go to, but I don't think the guy was too happy
所以显然他们两个都有派对要去，但我觉得那个男人不太高兴。
about it.
I don't think so either and that's the funny thing.
我也觉得，这就是有趣的地方。
I think a lot of girls are like, oh, well, my husband-to-be, he wants to have a party.
我觉得很多女人会想，哦，好吧，我未来的丈夫想办个派对。
It's okay.
没关系。
But the minute the girl wants to have the party, the guy is like, uh-uh, no way.
但一旦女人想办派对，男人就会说，呃呃，没门。
That's true.
确实如此。
I guess, but we can talk a little bit more about this towards the end.
我想是的，但我们可以在最后再聊更多这个话题。
Before we start on this really interesting topic, why don't we take a look at some of
在我们开始这个非常有趣的话题之前，我们先来看看
the language on Language Takeaway.
“语言要点”中的一些语言点。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
Well, Marco, the first few words are actually more wedding terms than bachelor party terms.
嗯，Marco，前几个词其实是更多关于婚礼的术语，而不是单身派对的。
The first one is best man.
第一个是“best man”。
Right, the best man.
对，“best man”。
So the best man is, who is he exactly?
那么“best man”到底是谁？
He's usually the groom's best friend.
他通常是新郎最好的朋友。
So the groom is the man getting married and his best friend has the position of best man.
所以新郎是结婚的男人，他最好的朋友担任伴郎的角色。
So he has some special things to do at the wedding.
他在婚礼上有一些特别的事情要做。
He has to make a speech, for example, and he has to stand next to his friend when the
比如，他必须发表演讲，而且当朋友结婚时，他必须站在朋友旁边。
friend gets married.
And it's just a very special position of honor that the best friend has in his friend's wedding.
这是最好的朋友在朋友婚礼上享有的一个非常特殊的荣誉位置。
Okay, and among those responsibilities, the best man is usually the one that has to organize
好的，在这些责任中，伴郎通常是负责组织
the bachelor party, right?
单身派对的人，对吧？
Exactly.
没错。
Okay, so best man.
好的，所以是“best man”。
And well, the rest of the groom's friends are also present at the wedding and they are
嗯，新郎的其他朋友也会出席婚礼，他们被称为
called the groomsmen.
“groomsmen”。
All right, so groom, groomsmen.
好的，所以是“groom”，“groomsmen”。
And so usually these are maybe three to five guys, three to five men who are friends of
通常这些人是三到五个男人，他们是新郎的朋友
the groom or brother of the bride.
或新娘的兄弟。
It depends on the wedding.
这取决于婚礼。
And they stand with the man when he gets married.
他们会在男人结婚时站在他旁边。
And so they kind of have a lot of responsibilities as well.
所以他们也有很多责任。
Okay, and the groomsmen usually are also present at the bachelor party.
好的，伴郎们通常也会参加单身派对。
Exactly.
没错。
All right.
好的。
Now moving on to a bit more colorful language.
现在我们来谈谈更生动一些的语言。
We have a place here, a strip club.
我们有一个地方，“strip club”。
Okay, so sometimes you see these in movies oftentimes or for example, the TV show The
好的，有时你会在电影里看到，或者比如电视剧《黑道家族》，
Sopranos, this is often a place where Tony Soprano goes.
这是Tony Soprano经常去的地方。
A strip club is a club, it's like a bar that's open most of the day and night where there
“Strip club”是一个俱乐部，就像一个大部分时间都营业的酒吧，那里有
are women who take their clothes off for money.
女人为了钱脱衣服。
All right, so you have the verb to strip, right?
好的，所以有动词“to strip”，对吧？
A strip club.
“Strip club”。
So the verb to strip means to take off or leave without something.
所以动词“to strip”意思是脱掉或失去某物。
Right.
对。
So you can strip off your clothes.
所以你可以脱掉衣服。
So it's usually used with clothes, right?
所以它通常和衣服一起使用，对吧？
To take off clothes, to strip.
脱衣服，脱光。
So you have a strip club and in the strip club, you have the, as you mentioned, the
所以有脱衣舞俱乐部，在脱衣舞俱乐部里，就像你提到的，有
girls that are dancing and taking off their clothes, they are called strippers.
那些跳舞并脱衣服的女孩，她们被称为脱衣舞娘。
Okay, so stripper is a person who takes off their clothes as their job.
好的，所以脱衣舞娘就是以脱衣服为职业的人。
And you can have male strippers or female strippers.
而且可以有男脱衣舞娘或女脱衣舞娘。
True.
没错。
So usually just saying stripper is a woman and a male stripper is actually a guy.
所以通常只说脱衣舞娘指的是女性，而男脱衣舞娘则是指男性。
So you have this club that's very common in many countries and well, the strippers are
所以这种俱乐部在很多国家都很常见，而且脱衣舞娘们
dancing and now they also talked about getting a lap dance.
在跳舞，现在他们还提到了要跳大腿舞。
Okay, now this is getting a little bit, a little dirty.
好的，这有点，有点低俗了。
Lap is a, well, it's not really a part of your body but when you sit down in a chair,
大腿（lap）是，嗯，它不是你身体的一部分，但当你坐在椅子上时，
your lap is the tops of your legs.
你的大腿就是你的腿的上部。
So you can, you know, you can hold something in your lap like your backpack.
所以你可以，你知道，你可以把东西放在大腿上，比如你的背包。
Or maybe for example, if you have a child that's three or four years old, you would
或者举个例子，如果你有一个三四岁的孩子，你会
sit him on your lap, right, on your legs while you're sitting down maybe in subway.
让他坐在你的大腿上，对吧，坐在你的腿上，比如在地铁里坐着的时候。
Right, or a laptop computer is the kind of computer you can hold on your lap.
对，或者笔记本电脑（laptop）就是那种可以放在大腿上用的电脑。
So a lap dance is when one of the female strippers comes and kind of dances on your lap.
所以大腿舞就是其中一个女脱衣舞娘过来，在你的大腿上跳舞。
Exactly.
正是如此。
And so it's a sexy dance.
这是一种性感的舞蹈。
You pay for it extra and it's something that is very popular with young men and people
你需要额外付钱，这在年轻男性和那些
who, you know, these grooms and groomsmen before the groom gets married.
新郎和伴郎们中间非常流行，尤其是在新郎结婚前。
Right, alright.
对，好的。
And moving on, we have the last word for today, gag gifts.
继续，我们来看今天的最后一个词，恶搞礼物。
Alright, gag gifts are joke gifts.
好的，恶搞礼物就是玩笑礼物。
They're joke, they're meant to be funny, they're not meant to be serious.
它们是玩笑，目的是搞笑，不是认真的。
And they're very popular at these kinds of bachelor parties and bachelorette parties.
它们在单身派对和单身女郎派对上非常流行。
One kind of gag gift that's just very silly is like a whoopee cushion.
一种很傻的恶搞礼物就是放屁垫。
You know, it's like a balloon you put on someone's seat and when they sit down, they make a farting
你知道，它就像一个气球，你放在别人的座位上，当他们坐下时，会发出放屁的
sound.
声音。
Right.
对。
So those are gag gifts.
所以那些就是恶搞礼物。
And for to joke around, it's not really useful.
用来开玩笑，不是真的有用。
It's not like giving somebody a t-shirt, right?
不像送别人一件T恤，对吧？
Right, or a gift card is a nice gift.
对，或者礼品卡是很好的礼物。
It's not a gag gift.
那不是恶搞礼物。
Right.
对。
So there are really, there are a lot of different types of gag gifts and actually some of them
所以真的有很多不同类型的恶搞礼物，实际上有些
are pretty good and funny like, you know, like spicy chewing gum or the electric shocker.
还挺不错和有趣的，比如，你知道，像辣味口香糖或电击器。
Oh, yeah.
哦，是啊。
When you shake somebody's hand.
当你和别人握手的时候。
That's really funny.
那真的很有趣。
Alright, so we've taken a look at a lot of words on Language Takeaway.
好的，我们在“语言要点”部分看了很多单词。
So let's listen to this dialogue again and we'll be right back with Fluency Builder.
那么让我们再听一遍这段对话，我们马上回来进入“流利度构建”部分。
Hi, honey.
嗨，亲爱的。
You'll never guess what.
你绝对猜不到发生了什么。
My friends, Julie and Alex, are getting married.
我的朋友朱莉和亚历克斯要结婚了。
Wow, that's great news.
哇，真是好消息。
They're a great couple.
他们是很好的一对。
I know.
我知道。
Anyways, I just talked to Alex's best man and he is organizing the bachelor party.
总之，我刚和亚历克斯的伴郎聊过，他正在组织单身派对。
It's gonna be so much fun.
一定会很好玩的。
All the groomsmen are thinking up all the wacky and crazy things we're gonna do that
所有伴郎都在想那天晚上我们要做的所有古怪疯狂的事。
night.
You aren't going to a strip club, are you?
你不会去脱衣舞俱乐部吧？
I don't want you getting a lap dance from some stripper with the excuse that it's your
我不想你以朋友派对为借口，让某个脱衣舞娘给你跳大腿舞。
friend's party.
Ah, come on.
啊，别这样。
It's just some innocent fun.
这只是些无害的乐趣。
You know how these things are.
你知道这些事是什么样的。
We're gonna play drinking games, get him some gag gifts and just have a good time.
我们会玩喝酒游戏，给他买些恶搞礼物，好好玩一玩。
Nothing too over the top.
不会太过分的。
Well, I don't know.
嗯，我不知道。
Come on.
拜托。
If one of your friends was getting married, I wouldn't mind you going to her bachelorette
如果你的朋友要结婚了，我不会介意你去参加她的单身女郎派对。
party.
Good, because my friend Wendy's getting married and I'm organizing her party.
很好，因为我的朋友温蒂要结婚了，我正在组织她的派对。
What?
什么？
All right, we're back.
好的，我们回来了。
So now, let's look at some of the phrases that were used in this dialogue on Fluency
那么现在，让我们看看这段对话中在“流利度构建”部分用到的一些短语。
Builder.
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建。
All right.
好的。
So at the beginning of this dialogue, we meet this couple, this man and woman.
所以在对话开头，我们遇到了这对情侣，这个男人和女人。
And the guy says, hey, honey, you'll never guess what.
然后那个男的说，嘿，亲爱的，你绝对猜不到发生了什么。
All right.
好的。
Okay, my friends are getting married.
好的，我的朋友要结婚了。
So what does this mean?
那么这是什么意思？
You'll never guess what.
你绝对猜不到发生了什么。
It's just a phrase that you would use to give really, really important or exciting news.
这只是一个用来传达非常重要或令人兴奋的消息的短语。
It's like, guess what?
就像，猜猜看？
Okay, so you'll never guess what happened to me.
好的，所以你绝对猜不到我发生了什么。
I won the lottery.
我中了彩票。
Right, it's so amazing or it's so uncommon or unusual that you would probably never guess
对，这太惊人了，或者太不寻常了，所以你很可能永远猜不到
that person won the lottery.
那个人中了彩票。
Okay, so you'll never guess what.
好的，所以你绝对猜不到发生了什么。
Right, you'll never guess what.
对，你绝对猜不到发生了什么。
Or you can say, guess what, I won the lottery.
或者你可以说，猜猜看，我中了彩票。
Okay, all right.
好的，行。
And our second phrase, you know how these things are.
我们的第二个短语，你知道这些事是什么样的。
Okay, so this is a phrase that people often use when they want to remind someone that
好的，所以这是一个人们经常用的短语，当他们想提醒某人
this is tradition or this is a habit, it's a common thing.
这是传统或习惯，是常见的事情。
And so oftentimes when like people are having problems at work and they say, oh, gosh, this
所以很多时候，比如当人们在工作中遇到问题，他们说，哦，天哪，这个
person's just not listening to me.
人就是不听我的。
Someone to help them out will say, you know, you know how these things are.
有人会帮他们说，你知道，你知道这些事是什么样的。
You know, it takes some time to resolve a problem.
你知道，解决问题需要一些时间。
Or you could say, you know, gosh, this is gonna be a horrible party.
或者你可以说，你知道，天哪，这会是一个糟糕的派对。
I don't want you guys to go to a strip club.
我不想你们去脱衣舞俱乐部。
It's so dirty.
那太肮脏了。
Right.
对。
And you'd say, well, you know how these things are.
然后你会说，嗯，你知道这些事是什么样的。
It's tradition.
这是传统。
You have to do it.
你必须这么做。
Right, so this is what he meant, right?
对，所以这就是他说的意思，对吧？
You know how these things are.
你知道这些事是什么样的。
It's like, I don't really have a choice.
就像，我真的没有选择。
It's a tradition.
这是传统。
This is what guys do when they're gonna get married.
这就是男人要结婚时做的事。
So we have to do it.
所以我们得这么做。
It's almost like saying, don't worry about it.
这几乎就像在说，别担心。
There's really nothing to worry about.
真的没什么好担心的。
Nothing to worry about.
没什么好担心的。
All right.
好的。
And our last phrase, and our last phrase is something that we'd never want to happen.
我们的最后一个短语，我们的最后一个短语是我们永远不希望发生的事情。
Something to be over the top.
就是“过分”。
Well, it's not necessarily a bad thing.
嗯，这不一定是坏事。
Okay.
好的。
So we could say that it was a really ridiculous party.
所以我们可以说那是一个真的很荒谬的派对。
It was really over the top.
它真的很过分。
They had a clown and they had people dressed up like Star Trek characters.
他们请了小丑，还有人打扮成《星际迷航》里的角色。
You know, something that is more than normal.
你知道，就是那种比平常更夸张的东西。
It's almost silly the way that it's all just kind of crazy.
所有事情都那么疯狂，简直有点可笑。
And yeah, it's too much in every way.
是啊，各方面都太过分了。
Right.
没错。
So it can be something bad, like for example, someone's behavior was over the top.
所以它可以是坏事，比如某人的行为太过火了。
It was too much.
太过了。
It was too intense.
太激烈了。
Or like, oh my gosh, did you see her coat?
或者像，哦天哪，你看到她的外套了吗？
It's really over the top.
真的太夸张了。
It's like purple with sprinkles on it.
就是那种紫色带亮片的外套。
Right.
没错。
So it can be used in different ways, but it usually means it's excessive.
所以它可以用在不同场合，但通常意思是“过度”。
It's too much.
太过了。
Exactly.
完全正确。
All right.
好了。
So some interesting phrases on this occasion as well.
这次对话里还有一些有趣的短语。
Let's listen to our dialogue for the last time and we'll be back.
让我们最后听一遍对话，然后回来。
Hi, honey.
嗨，亲爱的。
You'll never guess what.
你绝对猜不到发生了什么。
My friends Julie and Alex are getting married.
我的朋友朱莉和亚历克斯要结婚了。
Wow.
哇。
That's great news.
真是好消息。
They're a great couple.
他们是很棒的一对。
I know.
我知道。
Anyways, I just talked to Alex's best man and he is organizing the bachelor party.
总之，我刚和亚历克斯的伴郎聊过，他在组织单身派对。
It's going to be so much fun.
肯定会特别好玩。
All the groomsmen are thinking up all the wacky and crazy things we're going to do
所有伴郎都在想那些古怪又疯狂的事，我们那天晚上要做的。
that night.
那天晚上。
You aren't going to a strip club, are you?
你不会去脱衣舞俱乐部吧？
I don't want you getting a lap dance from some stripper with the excuse that it's your
我不想你以朋友派对为借口，让某个脱衣舞女给你跳大腿舞。
friend's party.
朋友派对。
Oh, come on.
哦，别这样。
It's just some innocent fun.
只是些无害的乐趣。
You know how these things are.
你知道这种事是什么样的。
We're going to play drinking games, get them some gag gifts and just have a good time.
我们会玩喝酒游戏，给他们送些恶搞礼物，好好开心一下。
Nothing too over the top.
不会太过火。
Well, I don't know.
嗯，我不确定。
Come on.
别这样。
If one of your friends was getting married, I wouldn't mind you going to a bachelorette
如果你的朋友要结婚，我不会介意你去参加单身女郎派对。
party.
派对。
Good, because my friend Wendy is getting married and I'm organizing her party.
很好，因为我的朋友温蒂要结婚了，我在组织她的派对。
What?
什么？
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So bachelor and bachelorette parties.
所以是单身汉和单身女郎派对。
Have you ever been to a bachelorette party?
你参加过单身女郎派对吗？
I have not yet, but one of my closest friends is getting married in a couple of weeks, and
还没有，但我一个最亲密的朋友几周后要结婚，所以我会参加并帮忙组织一个单身女郎派对。
so I will be attending and helping organize a bachelorette party.
所以你有什么想法吗？
So do you have anything in mind?
有什么计划吗？
Nothing I can talk about.
没什么能说的。
These things are meant to be surprises oftentimes, so I don't want to spoil it.
这种事通常是要保密的，所以我不想剧透。
But I will tell you that my boyfriend just organized a bachelorette party for his best
但我会告诉你，我男朋友刚为他最好的朋友组织了一个单身汉派对。
friend.
朋友。
He was the best man in the wedding.
他是婚礼上的伴郎。
And it was very crazy.
而且非常疯狂。
Did they also go to Vegas and do some of these things that we saw in the dialogue?
他们也去了拉斯维加斯，做了我们在对话里看到的那种事吗？
They didn't go to Vegas, but they did some of the things we heard about in today's dialogue.
他们没去拉斯维加斯，但确实做了今天对话里提到的一些事。
They went to a strip club, they got lap dances, they drank a lot.
他们去了脱衣舞俱乐部，跳了大腿舞，喝了很多酒。
It was very over the top.
非常夸张。
And I think this is something that most of our listeners probably have seen in TV shows
我觉得这可能是我们大多数听众在电视节目或电影里看到过的，或者在不同类型的美国文化曝光中看到的，这在加拿大和美国其实非常非常普遍。
or in movies or in different type of exposure of American culture, which is actually very,
我不太确定欧洲或英国的情况。
very common in Canada, the United States.
其实也一样。
I'm not really sure about Europe or England.
真的吗？
It is too.
我朋友说他朋友要结婚了，他们全都去葡萄牙待了一周办单身派对。
Really?
真的吗？
My friend said that his friend was getting married and they all went to Portugal for
我朋友说他朋友要结婚了，他们全都去葡萄牙待了一周办单身派对。
a week to have a bachelor party.
一周。
And I heard something about mud wrestling.
我还听说有泥浆摔跤。
Wow.
哇。
Well, I guess it's different in every country.
嗯，我想每个国家都不一样。
And this is the interesting part.
这就是有趣的地方。
We want to know how these things are in your country.
我们想知道你们国家这些事是什么样的。
Do you have any traditions or any fun stuff that you do before the wedding?
你们在婚礼前有什么传统或有趣的活动吗？
Maybe after?
也许婚礼后？
I don't know.
我不知道。
What about Ecuador?
厄瓜多尔呢？
We usually, we don't really have strip clubs actually.
我们通常，其实没有脱衣舞俱乐部。
So it's kind of...
所以有点……
That makes it easy.
那倒省事了。
Yeah.
是啊。
So we usually just do what we do every night.
所以我们通常就做每晚做的事。
Just go out with friends, drink and dance, play the guitar or yeah, maybe some gag gifts
就是和朋友出去，喝酒跳舞，弹吉他，或者给新郎送些恶搞礼物或搞个恶作剧，但不会太过火。
or some prank that we pull on the groom, but nothing too over the top.
所以是啊，我们真的很想知道你们国家的情况。
So yeah, we're really interested in knowing how it is in your country.
所以来EnglishPod.com，留下你的问题和评论，我们下次见。
So come to EnglishPod.com, leave your questions, comments and we'll see you guys next time.
在那之前，大家再见。
Until then, bye everyone.
再见。
Bye bye.
拜拜。